<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-28T14:42:20-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sebastian Arteaga | Design</title><subtitle>Sebastian Arteaga Portfolio UX Designer UI Designer Visual Designer Graphic Design Branding  
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/welcometojekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2017-07-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/welcometojekyll/">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Consilium Magazine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/consilium-magazine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Consilium Magazine" /><published>2017-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/consilium-magazine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/consilium-magazine/">&lt;p&gt;hello world&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">hello world</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsoft Garage Internship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/microsoftgarage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsoft Garage Internship" /><published>2017-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/microsoft-garage-internship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/microsoftgarage/">&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/garage.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-role&quot;&gt;My Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the UX/UI designer of the group, my role was to design the interaction between the hardware and the user; to understand the needs of the user of the keg; and know what kind of feedback the user needed from the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-research&quot;&gt;The Research&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research was divided in three fronts, first what other apps were doing with kegs, second, what kind of information were presented to the users on the screen, and third what kind of users would the device have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the research, an open source app on android, was discovered.  This app tracked the level of beer kegs. For the user interface, this app, used lists and icons w to show the different keg levels and types of beer. Not many other apps did something different from this, but the goal of all of these apps was more tracking the level of the beer kegs than actually controlling the flow,  or track the visits by user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very important to pay attention to the use of the Iced Coffee keg. Considering that currently the keg was not controlled, adding a device should not be a nuisance for the user. Different timed observations were carried out with the uncontrolled keg. What was concluded was that users took between 5-7 seconds to fill a cup. The fluctuation of time depended on the size of the cup, how hard the user would pull the lever, and the amount of gas pushing the liquid up. Some users, wanted to ‘top-off’ their cups,  adding between 1-3  seconds to the initial count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-design&quot;&gt;The Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what kind of user I was designing for,  provided me with the opportunity to understand how the device will interact with user. I imagined an experience that would feel seamless to the user, almost as if the device was not there, that the added step of tapping the ID would not impede the easy use of the keg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-user-flow&quot;&gt;THE USER FLOW&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user flow was designed with as few screens as possible, so the device would be ready to use almost instantly between each visit to the keg. Once the ID tag is tapped on the RFID reader, access is granted or denied.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/flow.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-user-interface&quot;&gt;THE USER INTERFACE&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the UI, after making a set of low-res mockups, it was clear that information facing the user needed to be as practical as possible. It was also necessary to change different elements in the UI as the delivery schedule got closer and one important part of the device had to be left behind. The UI was then suited for the the prototype that was going to delivered at the end of the internship, keeping it clear and succinct, with only a few elements on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The welcome screen will have show the type of coffee that is currently in the keg,  and an invitation to the user to ‘please tap badge’. Once granted access, the screen will show the name of the user, and a timer. This timer has two uses, the first one, it will inform the user that the app and device are running that has not crashed. The second one, it shows that in a certain amount of time the device will lock again, and no more coffee will flow from the keg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/lowresmockupms.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/highresmockupms-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/highresmockupsms-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>